Guide to the Center for Documentary Studies student projects collection, 1980-2011 and undated RL.01266
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Duke, Spring 2010
  - Capstone Project, Certificate of Documentary Studies: Illumination, Jennifer Kozin, .5 box
    Senior project by Kozin comprises nocturnal color portraits of Duke University students taken in various locations in and around the Duke campus, including campus classrooms, the Nasher Art Museum, Perkins Library, athletic fields, apartments, campus parking lots, bus stops, and a few nightspots in Durham and Hillsborough, North Carolina. The set starts off with two prints containing the project title and introductory text: "The following scenes were captured between the hours of 10 PM and 4 AM at and around Duke University from October 2009 to March 2010." Digital inkjet color prints measure 13x19 inches.
    - Illumination photographic prints, 2010, 26 prints (Box 54)
  - Duke, ARTVIS 218: Eye-Con, Jeffery, Kirstie, 2010, .5 box
    Contains iconic-remakes of well-known works of art, featuring Duke University students posing as Rosie the Riveter, John Lennon and Yoko Ono, the Girl With the Pearl Earring, Magritte's Son of Adam, Marines raising the flag at Iwo Jima, the Beatles crossing Abbey Road, and others. Prints are not captioned. includes print-outs of original iconic images with text by Jeffery. Digital inkjet color prints measure 13x19 inches.
    - Eye-con, color prints, 2010, 22 prints (Box 54)
- Duke, Fall 2010
  - Duke DOCST 135S, Intro to Audio Documentary, 1 folder
    Contains one CD-Rom on which each student's final audio project is accessible. The class was taught by Professor John Biewen.
    - Final audio projects, 1 CD-Rom (Box 74)
  - Gateway Seminar: Social Movements: "ALFA" by Risa Isard
    Gateway Seminar: Social Movements, instructor Max Krochmal. Digital materials include Risa Isard's oral history research on the Atlanta Lesbian Feminist Alliance. Interviews with Saralyn Chesnut, Elizabeth Knowlton, Lorraine Fontana.
    - Recordings and documents (Digital-materials RL01266-SET-0001, E-folder RL01266-DVD-0001, E-folder ALFA)
- Duke, Spring 2011
  - Senior Thesis: Beauty Pageants in the South, Nettles, Kim, 2011, 2 folders
    This collection was formed to complement Nettles's thesis, Victimization and the Ethics of Photography. Contains photographs taken chiefly at children's beauty pageants in North Carolina. Prints are titled and captioned on accompanying title sheet. Digital inkjet color prints measure 13x19 inches.
    - Beauty Pageants in the South, color prints, 2011, 12 prints (Box 59)
  - Introduction to Oral History
    Introduction to Oral History, instructor Max Krochmal.
    - Introduction to Oral History video of presentations, Two mini-dv video tapes. (Box 78)
    - Environmental Justice. Recordings, images, and documents. (Digital-materials RL01266-SET-0001, E-folder RL01266-DVD-0001, E-folder Feminisms)
    - Feminisms. Recordings, images, and documents. (Digital-materials RL01266-SET-0001, E-folder RL01266-DVD-0002, E-folder Feminisms)
    - Jomo. Recordings, images, and documents related to interview with Cleveland "Jomo" Davis. (Digital-materials RL01266-SET-0001, E-folder RL01266-DVD-0002, E-folder Jomo)
- Duke, Fall 2011
  - DOCST 117: Documentary Photography and the Southern Cultural Landscape, 2011, 2 boxes
    Student projects for this course consist of photographs that attempt to capture elements and themes of Southern culture. Photographs are typically accompanied by the student's essays, which explore the themes chosen and the unfolding of the projects. Unless otherwise noted, all prints are black-and-white and measure 8.5x11 inches.
    - Abramova, Ilona, 2 folders (Box 58)
      Digital color prints.
    - Averbrook, Carey (Box 74)
      Inside the RENA House
    - Jones, Michaela, 2 folders (Box 58)
      Streetball
    - Stillman, Josh, 2 folders (Box 74)
      Bluegrass in North Carolina. Digital color prints.
    - Thielman, Daniel, 3 folders (Box 58)
      Structure Poetry in Southern Cities Digital color prints.
    - Vo, Katie, 4 folders (Box 58)
      Community: Remembering Pauli Murray
    - Wiesner, Nick, 3 folders (Box 58)
      Durham County Wildlife Club Digital color prints.
  - Eloi, Marquise, 23 prints (Box 68)
    [Untitled] Digital inkjet color photographs explore abandoned homesites surrounding the author's hometown of Rolesville, N.C.; the images then turn to portraits of the author's Haitian-born family, playing dominoes and bezique and eating traditional Haitian foods in their Rolesville home. Prints measure 13x19 inches.
- Duke, undated projects
  These projects are missing information such as dates and project titles, or course title. They currently do not have release forms.
  - ARTVIS 114, undated project
    - Chapman, Tara (Box 65)
      "Documenting the Ronald McDonald House." Single black-and-white print of a boy with a Ronald McDonald sweatshirt and a hat, mounted in an 11.5x14 inch window mat that is glued to foamcore board. The image measures 9 3/4 x 6 5/8 inches. May be the missing print in the album listed below. Student essay is included in folder.
    - Chapman, Tara, 2 albums (Box 67)
      "Documenting the Ronald McDonald House." One black album with 14 black-and-white prints mounted with photo corners, documenting a guest house in Durham, N.C. for families who have children at Duke Hospital. Album missing one print: probably single print listed above.
  - Advanced Documentary Photography, undated projects (Box 67)
  - Paterson, Micaela, 2 folders; 28 prints (Box 74)
    "Documenting Southern Culture." Essay included. Images were taken in Durham, N.C., chiefly close-ups. Includes areas around 9th Street. Digital color prints measure 8.5x11 inches.
  - Picker, Sarah (Box 74)
    Untitled. Four black-and-white images taken at a convenience store/gas station. Prints measure 9 7/8 x 7 7/8 inches.
- Unidentified Projects, 7 boxes
  Eight photography projects created by unidentified students for documentary classes. Topics include religion, kitchens and markets, a goat herd, and abandoned schools. Includes color as well as black-and-white prints; the color are all digitally printed. No release forms.
  - [Unidentified project 1], undated, 4 prints (Box 65)
    Black-and-white images of old-time stringband, with several shots of dancers. Prints measure 8x10 inches.
  - [Unidentified project 2], undated, 4 prints (Box 67)
    Matted black-and-white images of a diner's kitchen. Prints measure 5 x 7 3/4 inches and 8x10 inches.
  - [Unidentified project 3], undated, 24 prints (Box 69)
    Digital inkjet color images of seafood markets. Prints measure 13x19 inches.
  - [Unidentified project 4], undated, 32 prints (Box 70)
    Digital inkjet color images of an abandoned school building's classrooms and grounds. Prints measure 13x19 inches.
  - [Unidentified project 5], undated, 21 prints (Box 71)
    Digital inkjet color images of the interiors, products, and personnel in two ethnic grocery stores - one Asian and one Hispanic. Prints measure 14x16 inches.
  - [Unidentified project 6], undated, 12 prints (Box 71)
    Each color image is accompanied by first-person captions handwritten by the individuals portrayed in the photographs, consisting of self-reflections on their religious customs and practices. Digital inkjet color prints measure 13x19 inches, mounted on black boards measuring 16x20 inches.
  - [Unidentified project 7], undated, 2 prints (Box 75)
    Black-and-white photographs of goats in a milking parlor, unknown location. Prints measure 11x14 inches.
  - [Unidentified project 8], undated, 6 prints (Box 76)
    Matted black-and-white prints of a Hispanic men's community soccer league in a game. Prints measure approximately 6x9 inches.